赖利·莫顿上场
Riley Morton coming up now.
之后是凯利 开局就是个漂亮的双杀
Kelly at second. Started the inning with a double.
局势看起来跟一小时前一样
That seems like an hour ago.
-亲爱的 你不是要倒垃圾嘛 -是的
- Honey, I thought you were gonna take out the garbage. - I am.
右侧高飞球 曲线飞出 界外球
High fly to right. Hooking, hooking- Foul.
-菲尔 -收到 马上去
- Phil. - Yes. Getting it.
我本来马上就要去倒的
I was- I was gonna get it.
-迪兰 -你好 邓菲太太
- Dylan. - Hey, Mrs. Dunphy.
我在等海莉
Um, I'm just waiting for Haley.
-你按门铃了吗 -我给她发短信了
- Did you ring the bell? - I texted.
她说她马上就下来
She said she'd be down in just a minute.
-那好 替我向她问好 -没问题
- Oh, great. Tell her I said "Hi." - I will.
迪兰 迪迪仔
Dylan! D-Money!
古惑小迪仔 快乐摇又摆
Chillin' with Dylan the villain!
-小迪的迪 迪兰的兰 -邓菲先生
- "D" To the "Y" To the- - Hey, Mr. Dunphy.
快进来
Hey! Come on in.
你刚好赶上看比赛结果
You're just in time to catch the end of the game.
我实在对棒球无爱
Oh, I'm not really a baseball guy.
海莉也向你问好
Haley says "Hi."
我刚刚是开玩笑的啦
I was just being facetious.
来 叔跟你说说赛况
Come on. I'll catch you up.
坐下 速度点
Sit it. Park it.
放轻松 人家又不会吃了你
Come on. I don't bite.
逗你玩儿
Kidding.
逗你玩的啦
I'm kidding.
看到那家伙了吗 就是他把比分拉平的
Okay. See that guy? He's the tying run.
特别有趣的是
Interesting story about him.
他一直被困在"二垒"那一步
He's been stuck on second base forever,
我敢说他要试着偷上"三垒"了
and I'm pretty sure he's gonna try and steal third,
我觉得这是个馊主意
which is just a terrible, terrible idea.
你跟海莉上到几垒了
How are you and Haley doing?
我真希望能跟你一起宅在家玩玩具飞机
I wish I could stay home with you and fly toy airplanes.
这可不是玩具飞机 曼尼
These aren't toy airplanes, Manny.
这叫模型 非常复杂的玩意儿
These are models, and they're very complicated.
要想成功让它飞起来 就必须了解螺旋桨
You wanna fly one of these, you gotta be familiar with airfoil,
拉你 空气浮力和推力等等
drag, lift and thrust-
全都是航空动力学的基本原理
and these are all principles of aerodynamics.
可盒子上写着"适宜12岁及以上人群"
The box says "12 and up."
什么
What?
下次你再跟杰一起玩飞机
You can fly toy planes with Jay next time.
-今天你得跟卢克待在一起 -为啥啊
- Today you have to spend time with Luke. - Why?
因为他妈邀请你去 所以你就得去
Because his mother invited you, so you go.
家庭成员间需要亲密相处 对吧 杰
Family needs to be close. Right, Jay?
这肯定是印刷错误
I'm pretty sure this is a typo.
男人得有点爱好 曼尼他亲爹可有一大堆
Men need their hobbies. Manny's father had many hobbies.
比如沙漠徒步旅行
Like hiking in the desert,
还有从那什么玩意儿上蹦下来滑雪的那个
that kind of skiing that they drop you from the-
那玩意儿用英语怎么说来着
How do you say in English?
-直升机 -没错
- Helicopter. - Yes.
有一次 他被人激将 竟然跟鳄鱼打拳击
Once, on a dare, he even boxed with an alligator.
那叫格斗 格斗
"Wrestle." You wrestle-
跟鳄鱼可打不了拳击
You can't box with alligators.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
就它们那小爪子怎么戴得上拳击手套
How would they get the gloves on those little claws?
-看起来不像小手手吗 -像个屁
- Aren't they like tiny little hands? - No!
好吧 现在我都忘了我们刚刚在说什么了
Okay, now I forgot what we're talking about.
不管怎样 对爷们儿来说 兴趣爱好很重要
Anyways, hobbies are important for the men,
无论是以命相赌的惊险爱好
whether you're risking your life...
或是离得远远地玩小飞机都一样
or flying little planes from a safe distance.
等等 这是要去哪儿
Wait, wait, wait. What are you doing?
我们得去买点尿布 几分钟就好
Uh, we're just gonna buy some diapers. It'll just take a second.
-是好市多超市哎 -没错 就是买尿布的地方啊
- This is Costco. - Yeah, which is where we buy diapers.
什么时候开始的
Since when?
你还记得几个月前我们收养了个孩子吗
Do you remember when we adopted that baby a few months back?
就从那时起
Since then.
米奇尔是个势利小人
Mitchell is a snob.
才不是 人家那叫有见识
No. N-No, I-I'm discerning.
势利小人的常用借口
Official slogan for snobs.
我们第一次见面时 他都没正眼瞧过我
When we first met, he wouldn't even look at me...
因为我只是一个密苏里来的乡巴佬
because I was a hick from the farm in Missouri,
而他却是个城市佬
and he's a big city mouse.
谁会说"城市佬"这个词
Who says "City mouse"?
与乡巴佬对应嘛
Country mice.
-我还是去车里等吧 -好的
- I think I'm gonna go wait in the car. - Okay.
你出去时能顺手把垃圾给倒了吗
Hey, if you're on your way out, can you grab the garbage?
-我已经倒了 -那好 用不着你了
- I got it. - Okay. We got it.
-他有点坐不住啊 -你想想看
- He's a little jumpy. - Oh, go figure-
哪个小男生想跟女朋友老爹一块玩儿
a teenage boy doesn't want to hang out with his girlfriend's dad.
我以为我们的关系早超越那个了
Thought we were past all that.
我还想
I'm all about-
-跟他培养超亲密关系呢 -是吗
- I'm all about taking it to the next level. - Really?
-我还以为你会踏实点呢 -本来也是
- Thought you were all about keeping it real. - Yes.
但是做得踏实一点
But the whole point of keeping it real is
也是为了能发展超亲密关系
so you can take it to the next level.
你是真不明白吗
Did you really not know that?
你跟我爸可没有发展超亲密关系呢
You haven't exactly taken it to the next level with my dad.
你在瞎说什么啊
What are you talking about?
我们都结婚16年了
We've been married for 16 years,
你在我爸身边还畏畏缩缩的放不开
and you still walk on eggshells around him.
什么 开什么玩笑啊
What? Are you kidding?
我跟杰那可是铁哥们儿
Jay and I are total buds.
你只是想找个伴出去玩玩吗
You-You want to just hang out?
我带上了6个好哥们儿[啤酒] 所以
Brought six friends, so that just-
就是...
That's-
曼尼把他最喜欢的桌游带来跟卢克一起玩
Manny brought his favorite game to play with Luke.
叫帝国时代
It's called Empire.
玩家要运用策略 攻城掠地 一统天下
You use strategy to expand territories and take over the world.
卢克会爱死这游戏的 他正在后院玩呢
Luke is gonna love that. He's out back playing.
我要出去买东西 需要给你带点什么回来吗
Do you need me to get you something while I'm out shopping?
多谢好意了 不过用不着 多谢
That's such a nice offer, but I think we're good. Thanks.
你看 这样如何
Okay. What about this?
你都不跟歌洛莉亚和曼尼打招呼的吗
You don't even say "Hello" To Gloria and Manny?
嗨 歌洛莉亚和曼尼 妈 到底怎么样
Hi, Gloria and Manny. Okay, Mom, what about this?
-不行 必须穿裙子 -妈 拜托
- No. You're wearing a dress. - Mom, come on.
怎么啦 今天一下午穿得像个女孩会死吗
What? It's gonna kill you to look like a girl for one afternoon?
要结婚的可是你的朋友 虽然我完全没听说过
But it's a wedding for some friend of yours I never even heard of.
没得商量 裙子你可以再去跟海莉借
It's non-negotiable. You can borrow a dress of Haley's again.
才不要
No.
那会让人错以为 我是不争气的海莉
That sends an ugly message- that I'm Haley.
比起逼着我穿裙子
You know, instead of trying to force me to wear a dress,
你是不是更该操心怎么让卢克穿裤子
why don't you worry about getting Luke to wear some pants?
什么 他这是要闹哪样
What? Why does he do this?
卢克
Luke!
拜托 快穿裤子
Pants! Come on!
我跟杰真是铁哥们儿 真的
Jay and I are buds, for sure-
但我们的亲密关系外界看不出来
but with kind of, um, an invisible asterisk.
他嘛 不是很爱说话
Um, he's not, uh- He's not a talker.
也不喜欢拥抱
Or-Or a hugger.
有一次他开车碾过我的脚
Once he ran over my foot with his car.
不过说实话 那时他刚戒烟很烦躁
To-To be fair, he had just given up smoking,
但基本上我们绝对是铁哥们儿
but basically we're-we're buds.
你非得在那傻站着吗
Do you have to just stand there?
你这样弄得我很不自在
You're making me feel uneasy.
老天啊 你就坐那吧
Oh, for God's sake. Sit here. Here.
像这样扶住机翼 我要调下这边
Hold this wing like this while I adjust this.
好的
Okay.
过来 坐这儿
Come on. Here.
不要太用力
Not too hard.
艾丽克斯 何不跟我购物去呢
Alex, why don't you come shopping with me?
也许我能帮你找到些你喜欢的东西
Maybe I can help you find something that you like.
多谢你的好意了 但她不怎么喜好逛街
That's a really nice offer, but it's not really her thing.
实际上 我挺想去的
Actually, I'd love to go.
老实说 你完全不知道我的喜好是什么
See, you don't know what my thing is.
你对我的喜好一无所知
You have no idea what my thing is.
我知道得非常清楚
I know what your thing is.
你就爱激怒老娘发火 你姐呢
Your thing is to provoke, just like your sister's thing...
就是一天到晚宅在房里
is to never come out of her room,
而你那个老弟呢
and your brother's thing-
就好这一口
Well, there's your brother's thing.
卢克 快穿上裤子
Luke! Put 'em on! Mm-hmm.
我跟杰的关系存在的问题就是...
The thing about me and Jay is our relationship's...
总是停滞不前
always been stuck in that,
总在原地踏步
that primal place where it started.
你懂的 他就像个护雌的银背大猩猩
You know, he's the old silverback protecting his females,
一旦有一只更年轻力壮的猩猩进入族群
then along comes this younger, stronger gorilla swinging in,
把老的那只打败了
beating his chest.
你懂的 很自然的 那些雌猩猩就会
You know, naturally, the ape ladies come running,
投怀送抱 求勾搭求包养
presenting their nice scarlet behinds.
猩猩爸爸想要阻止 但办不到
Papa ape wants to stop all that, but he can't.
你明白吗 生命规律就是那样的 我不是敌人
You know? That's-That's life. I'm not the enemy.
偷猎者才是
The enemy is poachers.
好了 别碰
That'll do it. Don't touch it.
好吧
All right.
-一起玩飞机去吗 -好啊
- You wanna go fly it? - Sure.
我拿了牙膏和香皂
Oh. Hey, I got the toothpaste and the soap.
真棒 现在我们都能开杂货店了
Good. Now we can open that general store.
我还以为我们只是来买尿布的呢
I thought we were just here to get diapers.
农场里有句俗话流传很广
We had a saying on the farm:
既然已经把骡子拉到集市上...
as long as you're bringing the mule to the market, you-
我感觉到你在对我翻白眼
I feel you rolling your eyes at me.
我们是在胡娇组织的一次传奇游戏夜上相识的
We met at one of Pepper's legendary game nights.
我对米奇尔有印象是因为
I remember Mitchell because
每当我兴奋地喊叫 他就冲我翻白眼
he kept rolling his eyes every time I would get a little boisterous.
我才没有
I did not.
有一点儿哦
A little bit.
好吧 或许吧
Yeah, maybe a little bit.
总之 我们在玩字谜游戏时
Anyway, we were- we were playing charades,
我不知道该怎么把线索用手势表演出来
and I had no idea how to act out my clue.
我只能想到这么来比划
And all I could think of to do was-
而小卡立马就回答到
And without missing a beat, Cam says-
卡萨布兰卡
Casablanca.
-我就这么比划了下 -卡萨布兰卡
- All I did was this- - Casablanca.
卡萨布兰卡
Casablanca.
我们能不能只拿尿布 买单闪人
Can we just please get the diapers and get out of here?
没问题 不过我想先去瞧瞧酒水区
Fine, but I wanna stop by the wine section first.
等等 这儿居然有酒水区
Wait. There's a wine section?
当然 挺棒的 就在轮胎区后面
Yeah, a really good one- just past the tires.
不可能 他们才没有... 天呐
No way. They do not have- Oh, my God.
天啊 小卡 是我想要的那种碎纸机耶
Oh, my- Cam. Cam. The paper shredder I wanted.
瞧瞧 五彩纸屑 还能横切
Huh? Confetti and crosscut.
棒
Yep.
老天啊 好满足呀
Oh, my God. Amazing.
是啊
Yeah.
小卡 这地方叫什么
Cam, what is this place?
此香只应天上有 是你的独家秘方吗
Those cookies smell like heaven. Your own recipe?
不 我只是随便丢进烤箱烤烤罢了
No, I just throw 'em in the oven.
但加了爱心作为神秘配料对吧
And added the secret ingredient of caring?
没错
Sure.
你跟卢克玩得开心吗
So, you and Luke having a good time?
我也不知道 他不愿意把头上的盒子拿掉
I don't know. He won't come out of his box.
也许我可以待在这儿 跟姐姐聊会儿天
Maybe I'll just stay here and spend some time with my sister.
对噢 好像严格说来 我是你继姐哦
Oh, right. I guess technically I would be your stepsister.
我妈不让我们说"继"字儿
My mother says we are never to use the word "Step"
因为那意味着不是真的
Because it means "Not real."
而我们是个真正意义上的家庭
And we are a real family. Mmm.
有什么问题吗 克莱尔
So what is the matter, Claire?
-什么 -你看起来不大高兴啊
- What? - You seem sad.
让艾丽克斯给气饱了
It's just stuff with Alex.
小孩子的问题 你懂的
You know, kid stuff.
小孩子
Kids.
别跟我提孩子 我学校里一堆小屁孩
You don't have to tell me. My school is full of them.
我想 午饭后我们能一起去逛街
I was thinking after lunch we can go and do a little shopping.
我可不会买裙子的
I'm not getting a dress.
我才不管 我又不是你妈
I don't care. I'm not your mother.
我知道 你是我外婆嘛
I know. You're my grandmother.
继--外婆
Step-grandmother.
不管怎么说 今天就把我当成你的闺蜜
Anyways, today, think of me as a girlfriend.
午后时光 两个小闺蜜一起找点乐子
Two girls out for an afternoon of fun.
你一般跟你的闺蜜们干什么呢
What do you usually do with your girlfriends?
不一定 逛街啊八卦啊喝酒啊
I don't know. We go out. We talk, drink wine.
-我能喝酒吗 -没门儿
- Can I drink wine? - No.
真"够朋友"
Some friend.
你可以跟我聊聊天啊 什么话题都行
Well, you can still talk to me about anything.
大人们都这么说 但都是口是心非
Yeah, adults always say that, but they don't mean it.
每次我妈说我想问什么都行
When my mom says I can ask her anything,
其实根本不行
I really can't.
我的问题直接把她逼疯
She just freaks out.
我不会被逼疯的 放心说吧
I won't freak out. Shoot.
那好
Okay.
你跟几个男人上过床
How many men have you slept with?
8个 下个问题
Eight. Next.
-我能试试吗 -不行
- Now can I try it? - No.
我也应该买一个 我爱死飞机了
I should get one of those. I've always loved planes.
如果上天能给我一次重来的机会
If things had gone a little differently in my life,
我可能是个飞行员
I think I would have been a pilot.
如果把遥控开关关了
Hey, what would happen if you turned the remote off
然后又马上打开会发生什么事呢
and then back on real fast?
你还真是个当飞行员的"好料子"
Yeah, you'd have been a great pilot.
那个 你能来个空中大回旋吗
So, can you do a- Can you do a loop-de-loop?
只要我想就行
If I wanted to.
不是吧 能让我试试吗
No way! Can I try it?
不行
No.
我知道你为什么爱玩飞机了 能修身养性
I can see why you like this. It's so peaceful.
就像世界的纷纷扰扰 全不见了一样
It's like the whole world just... disappears out here.
-我还记得有年夏天 -我跟你说
- I remember this one summer- - I'll tell you what.
我还会个绝招 叫"穿针引线"
There's another trick called "Threading the needle."
克莱尔和米奇还小的时候我常做给他们看
I used to do it with Claire and Mitch when they were kids.
-想看看吗 -要怎么弄
- You wanna try it? - How's it go?
从那边拿个圈圈
You grab one of those hoops over there...
然后走到很远很远很远的地方
and go to the far, far, far end of the field...
站着别动 我会让飞机从圈圈里钻过去
and stand there, and I fly the plane through it.
听起来真酷
Um, that sounds awesome!
-然后我也能试下吗 -不行
- And then I get a chance flying it? - No.
好吧
Okay.
这儿行不
How's this?
不够远 再站远点
Not far enough. Go on.
-好的 -越远越好
- Okay. Further down. - You can't go too far.
好的 我懂的
Right. Okay, I get it. I get it.
-站这儿行不 -挺好
- How's this? - Good.
站好了 千万别动
Now stand still. Don't move.
好的 来吧
Okay, let's do it. Whoo!
太酷了 我喜欢
Whoo! I love it!
我就喜欢
I love... it!
你拿飞机爆了我的头
You drove a plane into my face.
肯定是你动了 我说了不许动的
You must have moved. I told you to stay still.
-人家才没动 -闭嘴
- I didn't move. - Try not to talk.
我先检查一下飞机有没有坏
I want to make sure nothing's broken.
我跟艾丽克斯不止是意见不能统一
Alex and I can't just disagree.
她还总能把事儿闹大
I mean, she has to turn everything into a fight.
独立的女强人嘛
Hmm. A strong, independent woman.
听上去跟我认识的另外一个人一样
Sounds like somebody else I know.
但我从来都没有恶意
I was never hostile though.
我的意思是 关于穿裙子的问题
I mean, this whole thing with the dress-
海莉可从来不这样
Never had this problem with Haley.
也许艾丽克斯只是不想被拿来跟她姐比
Maybe Alex doesn't want to compete with her big sister.
或许她只是想做独一无二的自己
Maybe she's trying to create her own identity.
一旦她穿上裙子 她的独特之处就消失了
Put her in a dress, and she disappears.
就一下午都不行吗
For one afternoon?
要让我放弃做自己 哪怕一秒钟都不行
I wouldn't give up being myself for even one second.
有时候真不敢相信你才10岁
Sometimes it's hard to remember you're only 10 years old.
-10岁零9个月 -好吧
- And three-quarters. - Yeah.
我是米奇尔 你们要吃橄榄吗
Hey, it's Mitchell. Do you guys eat olives?
橄榄吗
Olives?
-特棒的橄榄要吗 -好啊
- Really good olives? - Yeah.
那我给你带了啊
You got it.
米奇尔 我找到尿布在哪了 就在那
Mitchell, I found the diapers. They're over here.
卡梅隆 你猜猜我发现到什么了
Cameron, guess what I found?
棺材
Coffins.
他们既卖婴幼儿奶粉 又卖棺材
They sell baby formula and they sell coffins.
你简直可以买到
You can buy literally buy
从你出生到去世需要用到的一切东西
everything you need from birth to death.
苍天大地啊 看看这些尿布
Oh, my God. Look at these diapers.
真便宜
Look how cheap they are!
你知道我们应该怎么做吗
Oh. You know what we should do?
我们应该买够一两年用的 对不
We should get enough for the next year or two, right?
那我们把它放哪呢
Where would we keep them?
-他们正好也卖棚子嘛 -真的吗
- They sell sheds. - Really?
你真要买个堆放尿布的棚吗
You want to buy a diaper shed?
我们要变成家里盖有尿布棚的家伙了对吗
We're those guys now? The guys with a diaper shed?
再拿两包
Just grab two more.
我才不要 米奇尔
I'm not grabbing two more, Mitchell.
我们该走了
It's time to go.
淡定嘛 我们得...不好意思
Come on, come on. We need, uh- Hey, excuse me.
-你从哪找的平板车 -就在那边
- Where did you get that flatbed thing? - Over there.
-我们也去弄一辆 -不是吧你
- Go grab one of those. - Really?
当然了 两辆才够
Yeah. Get two.
我在苹果酱那排等你
I'm in the applesauce aisle.
不管怎么说
So, anyways,
猜字谜游戏之后我们一起去喝咖啡了
after charades, we went out for coffee.
然后我了解到他喜欢艺术
And I learned that he loves art.
他会弹钢琴 还会说法语
He plays the piano. He speaks French.
-略懂 -听见没
- Un peu. - You see?
我对他的第一印象完全不靠谱
I-I misjudged him.
没错 我就跟好市多卖场一样
Yeah, I'm sort of like Costco.
我身躯庞大 土里土气 但引人迷恋
I'm big, I'm not fancy, and I dare you to not like me.
没错 而我就更像是那个...
Yeah, and I'm kinda more like that, um-
我们在巴黎逛的那个小店叫什么来着
What is the name of that little shop we went to in Paris?
你个势利小人
You are such a snob.
卡萨布兰卡
Casablanca.
我脚脖子上纹了朵小花
I have a small flower on my ankle...
还纹了一只小蝴蝶在我的 大腿上
and a tiny little butterfly on my... thigh.
大腿根部吗
How high up?
-靠近"中心地带" -你是为了性感才纹的吗
- Pretty high. - Did you do it to look sexy?
不 你是为男人纹的吗 我外公喜欢吗
No- - Did you do it for a guy? Does Grandpa like it?
否 否 是
No, no and yes.
恶心
That's gross
-继续说说你的耳洞吧 -才不要
- Let's go back to your piercings. - No, no, no.
我回答了这么多问题
I've answered enough of your questions.
现在轮到你来回答一个了
Now it's your turn to answer one.
什么问题
What is it?
你为什么不想穿裙子
Why you don't want to wear a dress?
因为我不想穿得像海莉和她那帮蠢伴一样
Because I don't want to look like Haley and her stupid friends.
我也穿裙子 我也不像海莉啊
I wear dresses and I don't look like Haley.
你就是海莉 40年后的版本
You are Haley, just 40 years older.
-10年后的 -20年后的
- Ten. - Twenty.
好吧 艾丽克斯 这你也要跟我吵吗
Deal. Alex, why are you fighting me on this?
其实 穿裙子也没什么大不了的
Just- It doesn't matter if I dress up.
只是我没有你跟海莉那么漂亮
I'm not pretty like Haley and you.
-胡扯 你美翻了 -才不是
- That's ridiculous! You're beautiful. - I'm not.
不过没关系 我聪明过人
But that's okay. I'm the smart one.
那个帅哥服务员可不知道你的智商多高
The cute busboy doesn't know that you're smart.
什么
What?
他每次过来续杯 都冲你微笑示意
He's been smiling at you every time he comes to the table.
才没有
He does not!
要不然你以为他为何就给我们上了面包呢
Why do you think we are the only people with bread?
听着 有一天你也会想跟那样的帅小伙约会
Look. One day you're going to want to date a cute guy like that.
等到那时候 你也会希望自己光彩动人
And when that day comes, you're going to want to look beautiful,
那时你就会穿裙子了
and then you'll wear a dress.
那你亲过女生吗
So, you ever kiss another girl?
跟外婆可不能这么说话
That's no way to talk to your grandmother.
我成长过程中 我妈对我严苛吗
Was my mom hard on me growing up?
是 绝对是
Yeah, she was.
但是你知道吗 当时
But you know what? Back then
贝蒂·弗莱顿和格洛莉亚·斯坦正火着呢
everything was Betty Friedan and Gloria Steinem.
她们都不明白...
They didn't understand-
-我们回来了哟 -好啊
- Hola! We're back. - Hello.
-逛得咋样啊 -非常棒
- Hey, how'd it go? - It was great.
-你跟卢克玩得开心吗 -这个嘛
- Did you have fun with Luke? - Well, not-
我们姐弟俩谈得很开心
We had a great time.
艾丽克斯 我想过了
Alex, I've been thinking, and...
你不想穿裙子参加婚礼
if you don't want to wear a dress to the wedding,
也没什么大不了的
it's not the end of the world.
没关系 我买了一条
It's all right. I bought one.
现在你看到她是怎么气我的了吗
Do you see how she has to provoke me?
我们下周再聊这个话题
We'll talk about it next week.
克莱尔
Claire!
让开道 进来
Clear the way. Coming through. Ow!
小心点 注意 伙计
Coming through. Easy. Easy, fella. Ow!
-我的脸得好好歇歇了 -你没事的
- I need to rest my face. - You're fine.
你会没事的 坚持住
You'll be all right. Hang on.
-老天啊 -进家门了
- Oh, my God! - Get the door.
爸
Ah! Dad?
小事故 没啥大不了的
Little accident. Nothing big.
-是飞机失事啦 -发生什么事了
- I was in a plane crash. - What happened?
我们正在玩穿针引线那一招 有人动了
We were threading the needle, and somebody moved.
哪有 人家才没有 你是故意的
No, I didn't. You did it on purpose.
他吃了止痛药 说胡话呢
That's the painkiller talking.
他有点晕乎乎的
He's a little loopy.
-到底有多严重 -机翼裂了
- How bad is it? - Well, the wing is cracked,
-螺旋桨也折了 但我 -我指菲尔
- the propeller's bent, but I can- I can- - I mean Phil.
-飞机失事了 -真"谢谢"你了 爸
- I was in a plane crash. - Thanks, Dad.
我又没让他站那 他非得去
I didn't ask him to be there. He insisted.
他非要冒险 就这样而已
He took a chance. This is what happened.
就像你上次开车轧他脚一样
Kind of like the time you ran over his foot.
你轧过他的脚吗
You ran over his foot?
-意外而已 -爸 你明明是故意的
- That was an accident. - You know, Dad, you did it on purpose.
我们都看到草坪上的轮胎印了
We all saw the tire marks on the lawn.
我那会儿刚戒烟嘛
I had just quit smoking.
瞧 你说得你老公心烦意乱了
See, you're upsetting your husband.
-水 -我去拿
- Water. - I'll get it.
你还好吧
Ay. You okay?
歌洛莉亚 谢谢老天爷 你在这
Gloria! Thank God you're here.
别担心 我也在这儿
Don't worry. I'm here too.
你是谁啊
Who's this?
不是我的错
Wasn't my fault.
我见你玩过无数次"穿针引线"那一招
I have seen you thread the needle a million times.
你从来没失过手
You never miss.
没错 我大概是宝刀已老
Yeah. I must be getting old.
你为什么就不愿承认呢 你不喜欢菲尔
Why don't you just admit it? You never liked Phil.
放下 才不给你吃曲奇饼呢
Put that down. You do not get a cookie.
我喜欢菲尔
I like Phil.
只是有时他有点太刻意讨好我了 你懂吗
It's just that sometimes he tries too hard, you know?
实在有点惹人生气
And it's just kind of- irritating.
好吧 也许他过于刻意讨好
Okay, maybe he tries too hard
因为你从来不主动和他亲近
because you make zero effort with him.
你知道吗 在我跟他结婚的16年里
You know what? In the 16 years that we've been married,
你有跟他说过一次你喜欢他吗
have you one time told him that you liked him?
-我只是没明确说"喜欢"二字嘛 -才不是
- Not in those exact words, no. - No.
你什么都没说过 爸
Not in any words, Dad.
你知道那让我心里多难过吗
How do you think that makes me feel?
你从没告诉过你的孩子你爱他吗
You've never told your son that you love him?
等等等等 什么时候上升到爱的高度了
Whoa, whoa. When did we jump to love?
而且准确地说 他又不是我的孩子
And he's technically not my son.
-那就是说你也不爱曼尼吗 -当然爱
- Ah. So that means that you don't love Manny either? - Sure, I do.
相信我 当我刚刚在公园玩飞机时
I mean, believe me, when I was in that park,
我真希望曼尼跟我一起
I really wished Manny was there.
为什么
For what?
那样你就可以用飞机爆他头了是吗
So that you could fly the plane into his head? Huh?
爸 多谢你能把菲尔送回家
Dad, thanks so much for bringing Phil home.
我在他头发里发现了你机翼的碎片
I found one of your little flaps in his hair. So-
实际上 这是副翼的碎片
Actually, this is called an aileron.
-用来保持...-现在重要的是菲尔才对吧
- It controls... - because that's what matters right now.
爸 请你离开
Bye, Dad.
-菲尔 -杰
- Hey, Phil. - Jay.
你是陶瓷做的吗
What are you, made of china?
菲尔 我只想让你明白我的歉意
Phil, I just want you to know I'm sorry.
不管是因为我失手了 还是你动了
And whether I, uh, missed or you moved-
-我才没动 -都好
- I didn't. - either way.
我只想让你知道 我喜欢你
I just want to say that I like you.
-真的吗 -必须的
- Really? - Yeah.
那你能说说喜欢人家什么地方吗
What do you like about me?
你是个好人
You're a nice guy.
非常努力
Try real hard.
没错
I do.
你还是个好父亲
And you're a good dad.
我是个好父亲 快来
Hey, I'm a good dad. Come here.
让我熊抱一个
Come here, you.
感觉真棒
This feels so right.
什么情况
What's going on?
发生了一点小意外
There was a little accident,
不过杰在对菲尔表明爱意
but Jay's telling Phil how much he loves him.
好吧 菲尔走运了
Oh. Well, that's nice for Phil.
真好
That's great,
他可从来没对我男人表现过爱意呢
since he's never said anything like that to my boyfriend.
-别提了 -不行 我气不过
- Let it go. - No, it's not okay.
不 米奇说的对 小卡 你也去抱抱
No, Mitch is right. Go in there too, Cam. Come on.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding.
-杰 -我来吧
- Jay! - I'm gonna get this.
-来吧 小卡 -就抱一小下
- Come on in, Cam. - Just a little hug.
-过来吧 -快说
- Get in here. - Say it.
-我勒个去 -快说 快说
- Whoa! Hey, hey, hey! - Say it! Say it!
小卡 我也喜欢你
I like you too, Cam.
-那你喜欢他哪一点 -天呐
- What do you like about him? - Oh, jez.
你从哪弄来的摄影机
Where did you get that camera?
从世上最给力的商场里买来的
Only the greatest store on earth.
谢谢你 爸
Thanks, Dad.
曼尼 照相啦 快来
Manny, picture! Get in there too.
快来 我的好小伙
Get in here, mi amigo. Oh!
别动 跟我说"茄子"
Stay still. Say "Cheese."
-别挤我 -茄子
- Don't push it. - Cheese!
拍好了
Picture.
-茄子 -茄子
- Cheese! - Cheese. Queso.
天啊
Oh, boy!
不觉得好像伸出手臂就能拥抱全世界吗
Doesn't it feel like these arms could go around the world?
我想我背部好像扭伤了
I think I strained something.
我一直想要个女儿
I always wanted a daughter-
给她穿漂亮的小裙子
to dress her up in pretty dresses,
给她做头发 美甲 化妆
do her hair, her nails, her makeup.
透露个小秘密 曼尼一岁的时候
No one knows this, but for the first year of his life,
我把他打扮得跟个女孩似的
I made up Manny like a girl
逢人就说他是我女儿
and told everybody that he was my daughter.
不过也就那么几次
Ay, but just for a few times.
我可不想让他对自己的性别产生困惑
I didn't want to mess with his head.
当他看到他小时候的照片
When he found the pictures,
我告诉他那是他已经死了的双胞胎姐姐
I told him that it was his twin sister who died.